

SUMMARY

Goal-oriented, enthusiastic front-end software developer with full stack experiences and background in financial analysis and reporting. Enjoys building user focused applications and collaborating with diverse cross-functional teams. Committed to product quality and positive user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Tyemill/Syntax, Seattle, WA (remote)

2021 - present

Software Engineer

- Implemented full stack features with emphasis on frontend for fintech website redesign and applications that provide in-depth investment analysis tools.
- Built frontend and backend features for classification tool that identifies company's DNA for investment.
- Led research on new tooltip libraries with pros and cons analysis; implemented recommended library and created how-to guide for other developers.
- Responsible for maintaining in-house SASS styling library (Tailwind CSS like) to achieve uniform design across projects.
- Collaborated closely with UX designer, product manager, and QA in building, testing and deploying features using Agile development principles.
- Created nightly data importer job using APIs to query data and Sidekiq background job framework
- Created feature implementation plans which included research, code design, and costing.
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails (Model View Controller, MVC), Stimulus JS, jQuery, ViewComponent, HTML, CSS3, SASS, REST API, PostgreSQL, Sidekiq, Redis, Minitest, Jest, Selenium, Cypress, Git, Github, Heroku, AWS; Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

OdysseyCommerce, San Francisco, CA

2020 - 2021

Software Engineer

- Built e-commerce/marketplace site for both consumers and business owners.
- Created features using React routers, hooks and Context API; developed reusable components.
- Created RESTful API endpoints and data handlers; built search functionality; incorporated third party API (Stripe) functionality.
- Technologies: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS3, Styled Components, Go (golang), PostgreSQL, Python, Git, Bitbucket

General Assembly Immersive Program, San Francisco, CA

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Software Engineer

- Developed and designed various applications using programming best practice, technical knowledge (JavaScript, React, Redux, Python, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, etc.), and optimizing code.
- Leveraged project management and leadership skills along with Agile Development principles to ensure applications are completed on time and meet the requirements.
- Completed over 600 hours of programming, projects, and expert-led instruction; gained a working knowledge of software development technologies.
- Technologies: React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS3, Node.js, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Python, Django, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL

Analysis and Insights Leader

- Built an action driven, user focused reporting tool by working closely with users and collaborating with software developers.
- Responsible for reporting analyses of clients' funds including tracking pre-IPO and IPO of technology and life-science industries, product trend, performance, and funding impact
- Slashed processing time in half (3 weeks to 1.5 weeks) by reengineering process flow and practicing Agile Development principles.

SKILLS

Technical Skills – JavaScript (ES6), HTML5/CSS3, React, Stimulus JS, Node.js, RESTful APIs, Ruby, Python, Go/golang, Rails, PostgreSQL, Minitest, Jest, Git, Github, Figma

Soft Skills – Empathy, problem solving, cross-functional collaboration and management, effective verbal & written communication

Other Knowledge - Banking products, finance, direct mail, credit card payment

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Engineer Certificate, General Assembly Immersive, 2020 B.S. Nuclear Engineering, University of California, Berkeley M.S. (coursework complete) Nuclear Engineering, University of California, Berkeley